JAMES V. KEEFE, JR.

Dover, NH 03820 Open to Remote Work (603) 534-8506 jvkeefe@gmail.com github.com/jkeefe77

SUMMARY

A driven web developer and decorated problem-solver with a background in procurement and public safety. Determined to utilize these skills and experiences to broaden my talents and build functional, approachable, and user-friendly web applications. Reliable team player who has the professional capacity to solve complex problems and mitigate risk while maintaining a clear focus on practical and sustainable solutions.

EDUCATION SUFFOLK UNIVERSITY Boston, MA

2003 - 2007

Bachelor of Arts, Sociology

Alpha Kappa Delta National Honor Society member

NEW HAMPSHIRE (NH) POLICE ACADEMY

May - August 2016

Received police officer certification from the NH Police Standards and Training Council

CAREER FOUNDRY

April 2023- present

Full Stack web developer certification (expected October 2023)

SKILLS CODING LANGUAGES / SPECIALTIES

- Full Stack web development (MERN)
- Angular
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Python
- Database fundamentals (SQL / NoSQL)

EXPERIENCE

CITY OF DOVER *Dover, NH,* **TOWN OF FARMINGTON** *Farmington, NH* 2016 – 2023 Police Officer

- Studied, learned, and applied applicable state and local laws and ordinances to serve and protect the community
- Cultivated and maintained positive working relationships with colleagues and diverse community stakeholders through effective communication and community-based policing efforts
- Navigated and resolved complex crises with steadfast professionalism, integrity, and empathy
- Conducted investigations by gathering evidence, interviewing involved parties, and analyzing information
- Drafted reports with observations, actions, and recommendations in accordance with department policies and procedures
- Provided courtroom testimonies to corroborate evidence related to violations against state law
- Trained and evaluated recruits as a certified Field Training Officer in compliance with state laws as well as professional standards adhering to the Commission of Accredited Law Enforcement Agencies (CALEA)

PARADIGM PRECISION Malden, MA

2012 - 2016

Material Coordinator/ Buyer

- Coordinated material movement between internal teams and outside suppliers for various aerospace engine components in compliance with ISO 9000 professional standards
- Exercised effective negotiation strategies in a fast-paced environment
- Supervised logistical routes and pathways for driver transportation efficiency

BOSTON FINANCIAL DATA SERVICES Quincy, MA

2008 - 2012

Defined Contribution Service Specialist

- Reviewed and analyzed distribution requests for various mutual fund accounts
- Worked with Quality Control department to investigate and resolve discrepancies in client supporting documentation
- Kept apprised of industry-related regulations including the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA) and the Anti-Money Laundering (AML) Act

PIONEER INVESTMENTS Boston, MA

2007 - 2008

Group Plan Specialist

- Supported retirement plan administration in accordance with governing regulations and company policy
- Coordinated with plan administrators and financial representatives to support benefits-related calculations in support of client requests

CERTIFICATIONS

- Defensive Tactics and Physical Fitness Instructor
- Crisis Intervention Responder, specializing in risk mitigation and de-escalation strategies
- Kempo Karate Black Belt (Third Dan)

VOLUNTEER ORGANIZATIONS

- Strafford County Child Advocacy Center
- Cambridge Auxiliary Police
- Harvard Museum of Natural History